applusvelosi.com 2018-11-25

# Privacy Policy For Websites/Apps -First Layer-

                                       Privacy Policy For Websites/Apps
                                              -First Layer-
              Basic Information regarding the processing of your Personal Data
 Data Controller          Applus+ Servicios Tecnológicos, S.L («Applus+», «Us», «We»,)
                          Calle Campezo, 1 edificio 3 28022 Madrid
                          More information
 Main Purposes            (a)  Provide and personalize our Services;
                          (b)  To deal with your enquiries and requests;
                          (c)  To manage our Website; and
                          (d)  To contact you with electronic newsletters and/or promotional e-
                               mails relating to products and services offered by Us and/or other
                               members of Applus Group, both national and international (a list of
                               which can be consulted at www.applus.com/appluscompanies) as
                               well as about events and news related to our activities (testing,
                               inspection, engineering, certification and related services), through
                               post, e-mail, mobile apps, SMS or other electronic equivalent
                               means.
                          More information
 Legal Basis              (a) Legitimate interests
                          (b) Consent
                          (c) Compliance with legal obligations
                          More information
 Personal Data            (a) Full name, phone number, email address, mobile phone number,
                               country of residence, name of the Company you work for and
                               position;
                          (b) If you are an Applus Services, S.A shareholder and use of
                               shareholder forum, voting platforms or contact us through the
                               channels provided, we will also collect digital certificate (to verify
                               your identity) as well as the number of shares you hold on Applus
                               Services, S.A.
                          More information
 Recipients               (a) Service providers and commercial partners.
                          (b) Entities of the Applus group. You can access the list of Applus
                               entities through this link: www.applus.com/appluscompanies.
                          (c) Security forces, judges and courts, regulatory entities, government
                               authorities or other competent third parties.
                          More information
 International            Your personal data might be transferred to, stored, and processed in a
 Transfers                country that is not regarded as ensuring an adequate level of protection
                          for personal data. We have put in place appropriate safeguards (such
                          as contractual commitments) in accordance with applicable legal
                          requirements based on the contractual clauses approved by the
Privacy Policy For Websites/Apps, May 2018                                                            1

                          European Commission to ensure that your data is adequately
                          protected.
                          More information
 Rights                   Among other, the right to access, rectify and erase the personal data,
                          to object to the further processing of the personal data, and to withdraw
                          consent.
                          In particular, you have the right to object to the processing of your
                          personal data, at any time, on the basis of our legitimate interest.
                          You can exercise your rights by contacting Us at
                          dataprivacy@applus.com, enclosing a copy of your ID or equivalent
                          identification document.
                          More information
 Extended                 Available at the following URL:
 Information
                          We recommend that you read it carefully.

                                                                                                    2
Privacy Policy For Websites/Apps, May 2018

                                      PRIVACY POLICY FOR WEBSITES/APPS
                                           -SECOND LAYER-
1. What personal data do We use
    1.1 Personal Data We collect directly from you
    1.2 Personal Data about third parties s
2. How We use your Personal Data and on what legal basis
3. What rights do you have over your Personal Data
4. How do We share your Personal Data and with whom
5. How do We protect your Personal Data
6. For how long do We store your Personal Data
7. International data transfers
8. Contact Us
9. Changes to this Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy describes how Applus Servicios Tecnológicos, SLU ( 'Applus+', 'We', 'Us')
collects and processes personal data about you, how We use and protect this information, and your
rights in relation to this information. Applus+ will collect and subsequently process the personal
data as the data controller. You may contact Us at:
Applus+
Address: Calle Campezo 1, edificio 3, 28022 Madrid
E-mail: dataprivacy@applus.com
 This Privacy Policy applies to all personal data We collect or process about you in relation to the
respect of the use of our Website, or through any queries or suggestions your send us through the
contact form available on the Website. 'Personal Data' means any information relating to an
identified or identifiable natural person who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by
reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier
or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural
or social identity of that natural person.
1.       WHAT PERSONAL DATA DO WE COLLECT
We will collect personal data that you send us directly through the contact form available on the
Website or through the e-mail addresses included for information purposes.
1.1      Personal Data We collect directly from you
The categories of personal data that We collect directly from you include:
         (a)        Personal details : full name;
         (b)        Contact details: phone number, email address, postal address, mobile phone
                    number and country of residence;
         (c)        Other details: name of the company where you work or which you represent;
                                                                                                        3
Privacy Policy For Websites/Apps, May 2018

         (d)        If you are an Applus Services, S.A shareholder and use the shareholders forum, or
                    the distance voting platform, or send us an email through the email addresses
                    provided, we will also gather data such as digital certificate (to guarantee your
                    identity) and the name of shares that you hold in Applus Services, S.A
         (e)        Information We collect automatically from you: further information about our use of
                    Cookies and Tracking Technologies is available in our Cookies Policy.
1.2      Personal Data about third parties
Where you provide Applus+ with personal data such as contact information about third parties, it is
your direct responsibility to inform such individuals of their rights and to obtain their explicit consent,
where necessary, to the processing (including transfers) of their personal data (including sensitive
data), as it may be deemed necessary and in compliance with applicable local data protection laws,
as set forth in this Privacy policy.
2.       HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA AND ON WHAT LEGAL BASIS
We use and subsequently process personal data we collect about you on the following legal basis
and for the purposes identified below:
         (a)        We will process your personal data on the basis of our legitimate interest, for the
                    following purposes:
                          Provide and personalize our Services;
                          To deal with your enquiries and requests;
                          To manage our Website;
                          To protect the security and/or integrity of our Website and IT infrastructure;
                          To understand how you use our services and to enable Us to improve and
                           further develop the features, performance and support available on our
                           Website, which may entail the provision of anonymous statistical information
                           about our visitors (however, without it being used to identify any individual
                           user);
                          As mentioned in Section 4 of this Privacy Policy, among other, for disclosures
                           to any of our employees, officers, agents, business partners, affiliates of the
                           Applus Group, who process the personal data for the purposes set forth in
                           this Privacy Policy;
                          To allow third party service providers and vendors engaged by Applus + to
                           access the personal data in order to provide Us with the services required to
                           fulfill the purposes set forth in this Privacy Policy;
                          For any disclosures to third parties required as part of due diligence
                           processes in the context of corporate restructuring operations in which We
                           may participate, in line with Section 4(d) of this Privacy Policy; and
                    Where Applus+ processes personal data in fulfillment of its own legitimate
                    interests, it shall always balance such interests against the data subjects´
                    fundamental rights and freedoms, and implements robust safeguards in view of
                    ensuring that their privacy is protected accordingly.
                                                                                                          4
Privacy Policy For Websites/Apps, May 2018

         (b)        We will process your personal data for the following purposes, provided that you
                    have granted your prior consent:
                          To contact you with electronic newsletters and/or promotional e-mails relating
                           to products and services offered by Us and/or other members of Applus
                           Group, both national and international (a list of which can be consulted at
                           www.applus.com/appluscompanies) as well as about events and news
                           related to our activities (testing, inspection, engineering, certification and
                           related services), through post, e-mail, mobile apps or other electronic
                           equivalent means; and
                          For any other purpose disclosed to you at the time you provide Us with your
                           personal data, to the extent that you have granted Us your prior consent to
                           that particular processing. For example, We will obtain your consent to collect
                           and use certain types of personal data when we are required to do so by law
                           (e.g. in relation to our direct marketing activities, Cookies and Tracking
                           Technologies, or when We process sensitive personal data).
                    If We ask for your consent to process your personal data, you may withdraw your
                    consent at any time by contacting Us at dataprivacy@applus.com, enclosing a copy
                    of your ID or equivalent identification document.
         (c)        We will also process your personal data in order to ensure an optimum level of
                    compliance with the applicable legal obligations to which Applus+ is subject, and
                    cooperate with regulators and law enforcement bodies where necessary, in line with
                    Section 4 of this Privacy Policy:
                          In case you are Applus Services, SA shareholder, to provide with the
                           shareholders forum and distance voting system, as well as other contact
                           channels as required by the Spanish Companies Act.
                          To disclose your personal data and other complementary information subject
                           to requests received from authorities and/or bodies with compelling power,
                           as required by the applicable laws or by law enforcement officers invested
                           with such powers.
3.       WHAT RIGHTS DO YOU HAVE OVER YOUR PERSONAL DATA
You have certain rights regarding your personal data, subject to local law. These include the
following rights:
        To know how We are processing your personal data and to access your personal data held
         by Applus+ and its affiliates, where applicable;
        To request the rectification of inaccurate or incomplete personal data;
        To request the erasure of your personal data when such data is no longer necessary for
         the initial purposes for which it has been initially collected, in accordance with applicable
         law;
        To restrict our processing of your personal data, under certain circumstances (in which
         case We will only retain the personal data for the exercise and/or defense of Applus+´
         rights);
                                                                                                         5
Privacy Policy For Websites/Apps, May 2018

        To object to our processing of your personal data, having regard to the given circumstances
         and for reasons related to their particular situation (in which case We will only retain the
         personal data for imperative legitimate reasons or the exercise and/or defense of Applus+´
         rights);
         This includes the right to object, at any time, for reasons related to your particular situation,
         to our processing of your personal data based on our legitimate interests or those of a third
         party, in which case We will cease in processing your personal data unless We are able to
         rely on legitimate reasons to do so;
        To request the portability of your personal data, which will allow you to obtain and reuse
         the personal data in a usable electronic format for your own purposes and across different
         services without hindrance to usability, including its transmission to another third party; and
        To withdraw the consent you may have granted to a specific processing, at any time.
We encourage you to contact us to update or correct your information if it changes or if the personal
data We hold about you is inaccurate.
We will contact you if we need additional information from you in order to honor your requests.
Applus+ is committed to protecting your personal data as described in this policy, and as required
by applicable laws. Should you have any queries or intention of requesting additional information
on how to exercise your rights or to effectively submit such a request, feel free to contact Us at
dataprivacy@applus.com, enclosing a copy of your ID or equivalent identification document.
4.       HOW DO WE SHARE YOUR PERSONAL DATA AND WITH WHOM
Applus+ will be able to share your personal data with third parties under the following
circumstances:
         (a)        Service providers and business partners. We will allow our service providers and
                    business partners that perform amongst others, web maintenance and other IT
                    services, marketing and communication, accounting, finance, legal and audit and
                    other business operations for us to access to your personal data. For example, We
                    may partner with other companies to process secure payments, fulfill orders,
                    optimize our services, send newsletters and marketing emails, support email and
                    messaging services and analyze information.
         (b)        Applus group companies (both national and international): we will share
                    certain information:
                    (i)      Related to your query or suggestion with other Applus group companies to
                             respond to it adequately
                    (ii)     To contact you with electronic newsletters and/or promotional e-mails
                             relating to products and services offered by Us and/or other members of
                             Applus Group, as well as about events and news related to our activities
                             (testing, inspection, engineering, certification and related services), through
                             post, e-mail, mobile apps or other electronic equivalent means; and
                    A list of companies within the                  Applus     group    is   available    at:
                    www.applus.com/appluscompanies.
                                                                                                            6
Privacy Policy For Websites/Apps, May 2018

         (c)        Law enforcement agency, court, regulator, government authority or other
                    third party with compelling authority. We will be able to share your personal data
                    with these parties where we believe this is necessary to comply with a legal or
                    regulatory obligation, or otherwise to protect our rights or the rights of any third
                    party.
         (d)        Asset purchasers and amalgamation. We will share your personal data with any
                    third party that purchases, or to which We transfer, all or substantially all of our
                    assets and business or with whom we enter into an amalgamation, consolidation,
                    merger or similar restructuring. Should such a sale or transfer occur, We will use
                    reasonable efforts to ensure that the entity to which we transfer your personal data
                    uses it in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy.
Because We operate as part of a global business, the recipients referred to above can be located
outside the jurisdiction in which you are located (or in which we provide the services), including
third countries outside the European Union ("EU") that are not regarded as providing an adequate
level of protection of the personal data. Please refer to the "International Data Transfer" section
below for more information.
5.       HOW DO WE PROTECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA
We implement technical and organizational measures to ensure a level of security appropriate to
the risk to the personal data we process. These measures are aimed at ensuring the on-going
integrity and confidentiality of personal data. We evaluate these measures on a regular basis to
ensure the security of the processing.
6.       FOR HOW LONG DO WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA
We will keep your personal data for as long as We have a relationship with you. Once our
relationship with you has come to an end, We will retain your personal data for a period of time that
enables Us to:
        Maintain business records for analysis and/or audit purposes;
        Comply with record retention requirements under the law;
        Defend or bring any existing or potential legal claims; and
        Deal with any complaints regarding the services.
We will delete your personal data when it is no longer required for these purposes. If there is any
information that we are unable, for technical reasons, to delete entirely from our systems, We will
put in place appropriate measures to prevent any further processing or use of the data.
7.       INTERNATIONAL DATA TRANSFERS
Your personal data will be transferred to, stored, and processed in a country that is not regarded
as ensuring an adequate level of protection for personal data under European Union law. We have
put in place appropriate safeguards (such as contractual commitments) in accordance with
applicable legal requirements to ensure that your data is adequately protected, on the basis of the
relevant sets of standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission available for
consultation at https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-
eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en. For more information on the
appropriate safeguards in place, please contact us at the details below.
                                                                                                       7
Privacy Policy For Websites/Apps, May 2018

8.       CONTACT US
Applus+ is the data controller in respect of the personal data we collect and process. If you have
questions or concerns regarding the way in which your personal data has been used, please
contact dataprivacy@applus.com
We are committed to working with you to obtain a fair resolution of any complaint or concern about
privacy. If, however, you believe that We have not been able to assist with your complaint or
concern, you have the right to make a complaint to the data protection authority of Spain (Agencia
Española de Protección de Datos) using their website https://www.agpd.es/portalwebAGPD/index-
ides-idphp.php.
9.       CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY
You are entitled to request a copy of this Privacy Policy from us using the contact details set out
above. This Privacy Policy will be subject to changes, as deemed necessary from time to time.
If We change this Privacy Policy, We will notify you of the changes. Where changes to the Privacy
Policy will have a fundamental impact on the nature of the processing or otherwise have a
substantial impact on you, We will give you sufficient advance notice so that you have the
opportunity to exercise your rights (e.g. among other, to object to the processing). Moreover, and
to the extent that Applus+ relies on consent for the performance of any of its processing activities,
We will make sure to request your consent where the aforementioned changes may have a
substantial impact on the relevant processing before these changes are made effective.
[MAY 25TH 2018]
                                                                                                    8
Privacy Policy For Websites/Apps, May 2018
